

# Nupur Somwanshi, DevOps Engineer

MUMBAI, INDIA · nupursomwanshi81@gmail.com

# DETAILS

Mumbai India

08411099849

#### **PROFILE**

Software Engineer with a strong math background and experience in predictive modeling, data processing, data mining algorithms, and building Machine Learning models to solve challenging business problems. Involved in Python open-source community and passionate about Machine learning and Computer Vision. Worked on ML deployment using Azure DevOps CI/CD pipeline. Have experience in Kubernetes, Docker, Azure Pipeline, GIT, GITHUB, AWS, Jenkins, Ansible, SonarQube, Nexus, Prometheus, Grafana and other DevOps Tools.

## EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

## Data Scientist, Tata Consultancy Services

Oct 2019 — Jan 2021, Mumbai

- Responsible for building Multi-Class Classifier for classifying Trade Finance documents for a BFSI client.
- Python Programming for developing the Machine Learning Models.
- Responsible for extracting business-relevant information from the above-mentioned documents using Image Processing, Text Processing, NLP and Spacy Models.
- Responsible for hyperparameter tuning of the models to get the desired accuracy.
- Responsible for building different models for different documents based on the information required from them.
- Responsible for taking all the necessary measures to avoid overfitting and underfitting of the models.
- Deployed Machine Learning solutions in Azure DevOps with CI/CD pipelines.
- Built and deployed many models like Decision Trees, Random Forest Ensemble Technique, CNN, RNN using Python.
- Built the project on Azure Suite using Azure in-built DevOps features like CICD Pipeline, Repository, Azure Test Suite.
- Responsible for creating Docker Images for the project and using Kubernetes orchestration
   Tool for deploying.
- Responsible for Continuous Management though Jenkins.
- Hands-on in other DevOps tools like SonarQube, Nexus, Helm, Prometheus, Grafana along with Kubernetes, Docker, GIT.
- Worked on Flask and Django for the application frontend website along with Python.
- Worked well independently and also as a team to solve problems.
- Organized and prioritized work to complete assignments in a timely, efficient manner.

## Analyst (Cloud Engineer), Deloitte

Feb 2021 — Present, Thane (Mumbai)

- Responsible for migration of multiple applications into a Private Cloud environment.
- Responsible for designing the Future Mode of Operation for the application migration so as
  to make it cost effective and efficient in the Private Cloud setup.
- Re-hosting, Rebuilding, or Lift and shift Migration of applications (depending on the Application structure).
- Responsible for the DB Migration of Large Databases and File Shared servers(NFS).

## LINKS

LinkedIn

#### **SKILLS**

Python

Machine Learning

AI/ML/NLP

Computer Vision

Data Analysis

Data Processing

Microsoft Azure IaaS and PaaS

Random Forest

Logistic Regression

Clustering

Classifier

Kubernetes

Docker

CI/CD

Microsoft Azure

DevOps

#### **HOBBIES**

Cooking, Cleaning, Organizing, Travelling.

- Responsible for finalizing Ports and Protocols and establishing Network communication between different components.
- Responsible for Migration of Applications that are hosted using Jenkins, Ansible, GIT and other DevOps technology.
- Responsible for designing Disaster Recovery Plan for the applications undergoing Migration.
- Resolved problems, improved operations, and provided exceptional service.

# LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

### **EDUCATION**

## Government College of Engineering, Aurangabad, M.Tech

2017 — 2019, Aurangabad

M.Tech Dissertation (2 years)- "Automatic Attendance System using Face recognition" done
in Python language and Machine Learning. In the dissertation project, the main components
were Computer Vision, Machine Learning Modelling (like K Nearest Neighbour) and
LBPH for extracting features from images. Creating a perfect dataset of images to train
the model, so as to get maximum accuracy. Published two research papers in reputed
International Journals for my Dissertation work in Machine Learning.

## ACE Academy Hyderabad, GATE Entrance Exam Preparations

2016 — 2017, Hyderabad

## Kavikulguru Institute of Technlogy, Ramtek, B.E.

2012 — 2016, Nagpur

- BE Mega Project Design and Stimulation of digital modulation techniques
   ASK(Amplitude Shift Keying), FSK (Frequency Shift Keying) & BSK(Binary Phase Shift
   Keying) using VHDL(Very High Definition Language) on Vivado ISE Design Suit.
- BE Mini Project Boolean algebra calculator using 8085 is an 8-bit microprocessor.

# Nutan Kanya Jr. College, 12th

2011 — 2012, Bhandara

Board - M.H State Board

Percent - 75.33%

#### Shrinbai Neterwala School, 10th

2009 — 2010, Tumsar

Board - C.B.S.E Board

C.G.P.A - 9.2

## **CERTIFCATIONS**

## Azure Data Scientist (DP-100), Microsoft

Aug 2020

# Azure Solutions Architect Expert, Microsoft

Apr 2021

# AWS Certified DevOps Engineer Professional, AWS

## EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

# Faculty Development Program (FDP)

2019, Aurangabad

Python Programming on Image

Processing

## PERSONAL DETAILS

Father's Name: Nareshsingh Somwanshi

Gender: Female

Nationality: Indian

D.O.B: 10/10/1994

## DECLARATION

I do hereby declare that the particulars of information and facts stated here in above are true, correct and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief.